<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red Hat on Archive of FeedHenry Developer Blog 2012-2016</title>
    <link>http://blog.feedhenry.com/categories/red-hat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Red Hat on Archive of FeedHenry Developer Blog 2012-2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 13:19:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.feedhenry.com/categories/red-hat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Madrid Hackathon</title>
      <link>http://blog.feedhenry.com/madrid-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 13:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.feedhenry.com/madrid-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Madrid, in a cool location in the centre of the city, Red Hat sponsored a IoT hackathon, 3 groups used RHMAP (Red Hat Mobile Application Platform) to build their entry for the competition. Over the course of two days (19 - 20th November), 11 groups and 6 individuals battled to find out who could build the best application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Windows-phone_20151119_22_36_23_Rich_LI.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Windows-phone_20151119_22_36_23_Rich_LI.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Windows phone_20151119_22_36_23_Rich_LI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Windows-phone_20151119_10_39_06_Rich_LI.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Windows phone_20151119_10_39_06_Rich_LI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We where there to get them going and help where needed. For most of them doing anything mobile or IoT was completely new, but they had some experience with Node.js, once we explained them how things globally worked and shown them how to build a simple &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; they where off. Remarkably, little help was needed the most questions we got where: &amp;ldquo;how do I do &amp;lsquo;xyz&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;what is the best approach to add a feature like this&amp;rdquo;. Although I had explained that you could develop / run things locally some contestants where comfortable using a online approach developing locally and testing the app in the &amp;lsquo;App Preview&amp;rsquo; window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t all work, there was some entertainment as well, there where some guys making jokes and some presentations about the possible future of IoT. Everything that happened was documented with some sketch notes. My portrait is also on it:&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Windows-phone_20151119_20_45_17_Rich_LI.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Windows-phone_20151119_20_45_17_Rich_LI.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Windows phone_20151119_20_45_17_Rich_LI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Windows-phone_20151119_10_39_06_Rich_LI.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo; teams won the big prize of 6000 euros, they got 2 checks like the one in the picture. As you can see from the eyes they pulled an &amp;ldquo;all nighter&amp;rdquo; to get something cool in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/20151120_123940.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/20151120_123940.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20151120_123940&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a very successful and cool event, for us an opportunity to see how easy it is to get going on the platform and get ideas to improve the getting started. Till next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FeedHenry and Red Hat Pushing ahead with Integrations</title>
      <link>http://blog.feedhenry.com/feedhenry-and-red-hat-pushing-ahead-with-integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 16:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.feedhenry.com/feedhenry-and-red-hat-pushing-ahead-with-integrations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been only 4 weeks since Red Hat acquired FeedHenry and we are delighted to be able to already announce the immediate availability of the first FeedHenry MBaaS Service for integrating with the Red Hat product suite. AeroGear - Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s open source offering for Unified Push Notification - can now be seamlessly accessed and leveraged as a microservice from the FeedHenry MBaaS Service Catalog. The driver for this integration is the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.be/&#34;&gt;Devoxx conference&lt;/a&gt;, where we will be showcasing the FeedHenry Mobile application Platform integrating with a range of Red Hat products and service in a fun and interactive demo as part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.be/keynotes-2014&#34;&gt;Wednesday&amp;rsquo;s Keynote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;aero-gear&#34;&gt;Aero Gear&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://aerogear.org/&#34;&gt;AeroGear&lt;/a&gt; project is a one stop solution for all your Push Notification needs - covering Native iOS &amp;amp; Android, Cordova Hybrid as well as Simple Push for Web. It is available to use right now from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.openshift.com/apps/9907#!overview&#34;&gt;OpenShift Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; - so feel free to give it a whirl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/AeroGear-on-OpenShift.png&#34; alt=&#34;AeroGear on OpenShift&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mbaas-integration&#34;&gt;MBaaS Integration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new AeroGear MBaaS Integration Services leverages the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.org/package/aerogear-sender-client&#34;&gt;Node.js module&lt;/a&gt; already developed by the AeroGear team and provides a simple, secure way to integrate Push Notifications into your FeedHenry apps. As you would expect, it uses all the out of the box functionality offered by FeedHenry MBaaS services such as interactive API documentation, wizard based configuration and a fine grained security model. The service itself is quick and painless to set up - simply provide the details of your AeroGear installation and credentials for the AeroGear app you want to use and you are ready to go. Using the service is just as easy - as a standard FeedHenry MBaaS service, you can call it in exactly the same way as you would any other MBaaS service - with a clean, crisp FeedHenry API call. For more information on FeedHenry MBaaS Services, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/98683877&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feedhenry.com/contact/&#34;&gt;send us a message&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.feedhenry.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/AeroGear-MBaaS-Service.png&#34; alt=&#34;AeroGear MBaaS Service&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great first step in integration with the superb Red Hat product suite and is just a taster of things to come. Stay tuned for more MBaaS integrations to Red Hat product in the coming months and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devoxx.be/&#34;&gt;Devoxx website&lt;/a&gt; for lots more information on what&amp;rsquo;s coming up at this excellent conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>