<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ios7 on Archive of FeedHenry Developer Blog 2012-2016</title>
    <link>http://feedhenrydevblogarchive.github.io/tags/ios7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ios7 on Archive of FeedHenry Developer Blog 2012-2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 10:04:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://feedhenrydevblogarchive.github.io/tags/ios7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A reminder to all developers about the iOS7 SDK</title>
      <link>http://feedhenrydevblogarchive.github.io/reminder-developers-ios7-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 10:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://feedhenrydevblogarchive.github.io/reminder-developers-ios7-sdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular features in the FeedHenry Platform is our &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.feedhenry.com/v2/app_building_and_submission.html&#34;&gt;Cloud Binary Build Service&lt;/a&gt;. This enables you to build Hybrid iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Blackberry Apps from within our web-based Studio rather than needing all of the tools on your own machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://feedhenrydevblogarchive.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/wtf4.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://feedhenrydevblogarchive.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/wtf4.png&#34; alt=&#34;wtf4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an iOS developer, you are probably aware that all apps submitted to the App Store after Feburary 1st have to be built with the iOS 7 SDK. Of course, if you are building locally on your own machine you need to update your setup. The big advantage of our Build Service is that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about that and we fully support the iOS7 SDK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in both cases there are two small extra things to be aware of related to the status bar and new icon dimensions. Please check out all of the details &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.feedhenry.com/v2/ios_7_support.html&#34;&gt;over on our docs site&lt;/a&gt;. If you run into any issues at all, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact our support department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for some very exciting news about our build capabilities in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>